Mayer Collection of Fat Liberation 1990.0057
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
Mayer Collection of Fat Liberation
undated, 1967-1983
1990.0057
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
0.75 Linear feet
Researcher and activist in the fat liberation movement and graduate student at the University of Connecticut; also known by the pseudonym Aldebaran.
Mayer, Vivian
Biography
Researcher and activist in the fat liberation movement and graduate student at the University of Connecticut; also known by the pseudonym Aldebaran.
Scope and Content
Correspondence relating to fat Americans and strategies for their liberation and societal restraints, chiefly with persons associated with Fat Underground (Los Angeles), Fat Liberation Front (New Haven), Fat Liberator Publications (New Haven, Minneapolis), and National Association to Aid Fat Americans. Related books, comic books, pamphlets, periodicals and boxed game have been removed from the collection and cataloged as part of the Alternative Press Collection. Items with a ∅ symbol have not been retained in the collection.
Arrangement
Series I: Correspondence ( undated, 1973-1983 )
Series II: Books and Periodicals ( undated, 1967-1983 )
Series III: Comic Books, Pamphlets, Publications ( undated 1973-1982 )
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
Twenty buttons have been transferred to the APC Button Collection.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Vivian Mayer.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to alternative and minority publications, presses, cultures and lifestyles. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Allon, Natalie; Bas Hannah, Sharon; Bremer, Anne-Marie; Demarest, Merry; Denne, Diane, Diane; Meyerding, Jane; Niedershuh, Karl; Nyman, Sue—Correspondence.; Rome, Esther; Schoenfielder, Lisa; Stein, Judith; Wieser, Barb—Correspondence.; Williams, Peggy—Correspondence.; Willimas, Russell—Correspondence.; Wolfe, Louise—Correspondence.; Wooley, Susan—Correspondence.; Wooley, Wayne—Correspondence.; Correspondence; Ephemera; Food habits; Mental health; Obesity; Political activists; Publications; Weight loss; Women
- Series I: Correspondence, undated, 1973-1983
  - Allon, Natalie, 1979-1980 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Bas Hannah, Sharon, 1976-1980 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Bremmer, Anne Marie, 1979-1980 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Demarest, Merry, 1977-1979 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Denne, Diane, 1973-1980 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Fagan, Reanne, 1979-1980 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Freespirit, Judy, 1979-1982 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Haskew, Paul, 1981-1982 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Kelly, 1980-1982 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Lepoff, Laurie Ann, 1976-1980 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - Meyerding, Janey, 1980-1982 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - National Association to Aid Fat Americans, 1976-1979 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
  - Niedershuh, Karl, undated, 1980-81 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
  - Nyman, Sue, 1982 (Box 1:, Folder 14)
  - Rome, Esther, 1980-1983 (Box 1:, Folder 15)
  - Stein, Judith, 1979-1980 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
  - Weiser, Barbara and Schoenfielder, Lisa (editors), undated, 1981-1983 (Box 1:, Folder 17)
  - Williams, Peggy and Russell, 1979-1980 (Box 1:, Folder 18)
  - Wolfe, Louise, 1981-1982 (Box 1:, Folder 19)
  - Woolley, Susan and Wayne, 1976-1981 (Box 1:, Folder 20)
  - Related Correspondence, articles and information
    - Personal, 1977-1983 (Box 1:, Folder 21)
    - “Struggle” Correspondence, 1977-1981 (Box 2:, Folder 22)
    - Discrimination, 1977-1980 (Box 2:, Folder 23)
    - Media, 1980-1981 (Box 2:, Folder 24)
    - Shadow on a Tightrope, 1977-1981 (Box 2:, Folder 25)
    - Requests for Information, 1980-1983 (Box 2:, Folder 26)
    - Ephemera, undated, 1979 (Box 2:, Folder 27)
    - Fat Liberation Resource Lists, 1980 (Box 2:, Folder 28)
    - Fat Underground v. NBC, undated, 1975 (Box 2:, Folder 29)
    - Announcements, undated, 1979-82 (Box 2:, Folder 30)
    - Meetings, Workshops, Conferences, 1973-1982 (Box 2:, Folder 31)
    - Munter, Carol, 1977 (Box 2:, Folder 32)
    - National Association to Aid Fat Americans, 1977-1981 (Box 2:, Folder 33)
    - Various forms of the literature package by the Los Angeles Fat Underground, 1974-1977 (Box 2:, Folder 34)
    - Bibiography on fat, women, and health, 1982 (Box 2:, Folder 35)
    - Health of fat women, circa 1970 (Box 2:, Folder 36)
- Series II: Books and periodicals, undated, 1967-1983
  General note
  (these titles have been catalogued unless otherwise noted, please check the catalog for appropriate references)
  - Abundantly Yours. Spring and Summer Collection. APC, 1978.
  - Against the Wall. Vol. 7, #3. Westfield, NJ:, (?). APC File, 1978
  - Ample Apple Bulletin. Seattle, WA: NAAFA. Vol. 2,#7-8, 10-12; Vol. 3, #1-6; loose pages; APC File., 1982-1983.
  - Alinsky, Saul D. Rules for Radicals. A Practical Primer from Realistic Radicals. New York: Vintage Books, APC Bk 630., 1972.
  - AWIS Newsletter. Washington, D.C.: Association for Women in Science. Vol. 10, #2, 6; Vol. 11, 1-4; Vol. 12, #1; APC, 1981-1983.
  - Berg, Peter. Figures of Regulation. Guides for Re-Balancing Society with The Biosphere. San Francisco: Planet Drum Foundation, ∅, 1982.
  - Buckhout, Robert, ed. Toward Social Change; a handbook for those who will. New York: Harper ☀ Row, Publishers, APC Bk f167., 1971.
  - Caddy, Eileen. The Living Word. Forres, Scotland: Findhorn Foundation, ∅, 1977.
  - Catholic Agitator. Los Angeles, CA: Los Angeles Catholic Worker. Vol. 8, #5, APC Folio., 1978.
  - Estrin, Marc. Recreation: Some Notes on What's What and What You Might be able to do About What's What. New York: Dell Publishing Co., Inc., APC Bk 632., 1971.
  - Fat Activists Together Newsletter. Issues 1-7, Loose, unidentified pages. APC, 1980-1982.
  - Fat Review. Connecticut Chapter, NAAFA. APC, May 1976, Summer 1976, August/September 1978.
  - Ferguson, Rowena. Editing the Small Magazine. 2nd edition revised. New York: Columbia University Press, ∅, 1976.
  - Forcade, Thomas King, ed. Underground Press Anthology. New York: Ace Books, APC Bk 635., 1972.
  - Friendly Woman. Santa Cruz, CA: Santa Cruz Friends Meeting. Vol. 5, #7, APC, Summer 1982.
  - Friends of the Earth. Nash, Hugh, ed. Progress as if Survival Mattered. A Handbook for a Conserver Society. San Francisco: Friends of the Earth, APC Bk f168., 1977.
  - Fujii, Nichidatsu. The Time Has Come to Save the World from Total Destruction: Appeal from a Japanese Buddhist Monk. Translated by Yumiko Miyazaki. `Sarvodaya' Monthly Special Number. Tokyo, Japan: Japan-Bharat Sarvodaya Mitrata Sanga, ∅, 1982.
  - Gold, Robert S., ed. The Rebel Culture. New York: Dell Publishing Co., Inc., APC Bk 633., 1970.
  - Gruen, John. The New Bohemia: The Combine Generation. New York: Grosset & Dunlap, B4386. ∅, 1967.
  - Hoffman, Abbie. Revolution for the Hell of It. New York: Dial Press, APC Bk 631., 1970.
  - Kornbluth, Jesse, ed. Notes from the New Underground. An Anthology. New York: The Viking Press, C1963. ∅, 1968.
  - Laurel, Alicia Bay. Living on the Earth. New York: Vintage Books, Random House, APC Bk f169., 1971.
  - Lipset, Seymour Martin and Sheldon S. Wolin, eds. The Berkeley Student Revolt: Facts and Interpretations. Garden City, N. Y.: Anchor Books, APC Bk 629., 1965.
  - Medical Self-Care. Access to Medical Tools. Inverness, CA: Cindy Omaha. Number 4, APC Journal., 1978.
  - Program. Lesbian/Gay Freedom Day. San Francisco, CA. APC, 1982.
  - Newsletter. Bellrose, NY: National Association to Aid Fat Americans, Inc. Vol. 3, #1-3, Vol. 5, # 4-6; Vol. 6, # 1, 3-6; Vol. 7, # 1-6; Vol. 8, # 1-6; Vol. 9, # 1. APC, 1973-1981.
  - NAAFA `Xtra. Bellrose, NY: National Association to Aid Fat Americans, Inc. No. 1-3, APC, 1980-1981.
  - Roberts, Ron E. The New Communes. Coming Together in America. Englewood Cliffs, N.J.: Prentice-Hall, Inc., APC Bk 627., 1971.
  - RT: A Journal of Radical Therapy. West Somerville, MA: Radical Therapist. Vol. 4, # 8, APC Journal., November 1975.
  - Rubin, Jerry. Do It! Scenarios of the Revolution. New York: Simon and Schuster, B3174. ∅, 1970.
  - Sale, Kirkpatrick. sds. New York: Vintage Books, APC Bk 628., 1974.
  - Schrank, Jeffrey. The Seed Catalog: A Guide to Teaching/Learning Materials. Boston: Beacon Press, APC Bk f170., 1974.
  - Second Wave: A Magazine of the New Feminism. Cambridge, MA: The Second Wave, Inc. Vol. 5, #1, APC Journal., Spring/Summer 1977.
  - Sister's Grimm. Connecticut's Feminist Publication. New Haven, CT: Sister. Vol. 6, # 12 (2 copies). APC Journal.
  - Slim News. Brooklyn, NY: Uplift, Inc. Vol. 1, #1. APC
  - Sprague, W.D. Case Histories from the Communes. New York: Lancer Books, APC Bk 634, 1972.
  - Taylor, Harold. How to Change Colleges: Notes on Radical Reform. New York: Holt, Rinehart and Winston, ∅, 1971.
  - Update. Cambridge, MA: Women's Community Health Center. APC, February/ March 1981.
  - Weiner, Rex and Deanne Stillman. Woodstock Census: The Nationwide Survey of the Sixties Generation. New York: The Viking Press, ∅, 1979.
- Series III: Comic Books, Pamphlets and Publications, undated, 1973-1982
  - Weiner, Rex Feed, Need, Greed. Where will it Lead? A Classroom approach to world hunger and population growth. Jamaica Plan, MA: SESPA, Science Teaching Group, APC Pam 889., 1974.
  - Weiner, Rex For the “overweight” Teenager. Westbury, NY: NAAFA, Education Committee, APC, 197?
  - Weiner, Rex James Bond 007 Tarot Game. New York: U.S. Games Systems, Inc. ∅, undated
  - Weiner, Rex To Serve the Rich. An ETR Pamphlet. APC Pam 353.
  - Bas Hannah, Sharon. Fat Womon/renaissance. Poems. Santa Monica, CA: Nomad Press, APC, 1978.
  - Bentley, Caryl B. Meeting Lisa. Minneapolis, MN: Fat Liberator Publications, APC, 1980.
  - Brown, Linda. Canta una Mujer. San Diego: Athena Press, APC Pam. 1081., 1971.
  - Donahue, Phil. Donahue. Transcript #04063. Appearances: Judy Freespirit, Nancy Thomas, Louise Wolf. Cincinnati, OH: Multimedia Program Productions, APC, 1982.
  - Fat Liberation Front. The Calorie Controversy—Who's Cheating? (How academic psychology oppresses fat people). Minneapolis, MN: Fat Liberation Publications, APC Pam 592., 1978.
  - Fat Liberation Front. A Fat Women's Problem-Solving Group: Radical Change. New Haven, CT: Fat Liberation Publications/Fat Liberation Front, APC Pam 593., 1978.
  - Fat Underground. Health of Fat Women...The Real Problem. Venice, CA: Fat Underground, APC, undated
  - Fat Underground Collective. Fat Underground: An Introduction to Fat Militancy. Minneapolis, MN: Fat Liberator Publications, (4 versions). APC Pam 594., undated
  - Forfreedom, Ann, comp. “Bibliography on Amazons, Matriarchs, and Lesbian culture”. N.P.: Ann Forfreedom, APC, undated
  - Forfreedom, Ann. Calafia, The Black Amazon Queen of California. San Diego, CA: Andromeda Press, APC, 1973.
  - Forfreedom, Ann. The Labrys of the Amazons. N.P.: Ann Forfreedom, APC, 1973.
  - Forfreedom, Ann. The Original Santa Claus. San Diego, CA: Athena Press, APC, 1973.
  - Forfreedom, Ann. “Sappha of Lesbos”. Article researched for the Feminist History Research Project. Venice, CA: Feminist History Research project, APC, 1973.
  - Gregory, Roberta. Dynamite Damsels. Long Beach, CA: Roberta Gregory, APC Bk 638., 1976.
  - K., Doris. Ordinary Hassles (an interview). Minneapolis, MN: Fat Liberator Publications, APC, 1978.
  - Kominsky, Aline and Diane Noomin. Twisted Sisters. Berkeley, CA: Last Gasp, APC, 1976.
  - Los Angeles Fat Underground. The Medical Politics of being Fat. Santa Monica: L.A. Fat Underground. APC, 1975.
  - Ludwig, Mary Ann. “Calorie Counters are losers.” Storrs, CT: University of Connecticut, Student Health Services, APC, 1982.
  - Marrs, Lee. The Further Fattening Adventures of Pudge, Girl Blimp. Issues #1-2. Berkeley, CA: Last Gasp, APC, 1973, 1975.
  - Mayer, Vivian. “Bibliography on fat, women and health.” APC, 1982.
  - Mayer, Vivian. The Fat Illusion. Minneapolis, MN: Fat Liberation Publications, APC Pam 591., 1978.
  - Mayer, Vivian. Fat Liberation. APC, 197?
  - Mayer, Vivian. Fat Liberation—A Luxury? Minneapolis, MN: Fat Liberation Publications, Reprint. APC, 1977.
  - National Association to Aid Fat Americans. The First Fat Liberator. Westbury, NY: Fat Liberator Publications, APC, 1980.
  - National Association to Aid Fat Americans. “First Western Regional NAAFA Convention, San Francisco Chapter”. (2 programs) APC, 1982
  - Stein, Judith A. Proceedings of the First Feminist Fat Activists' Working Meeting. Minneapolis, MN: Fat Liberator Publications, APC, 1980.
  - Wings, Mary. Dyke Shorts. Oakland, CA: Mary Wings, APC, 1978.
    ∅ This item was not retained in the collection.